http://www.asc.memberlodge.com/privacy-policy

Menu
Log in
ASC Home
About ASC
New to Sailing?
Committee
Virtual Sailing!
Membership Renewal
Privacy settings.
About ASC
New to Sailing?
Committee
Virtual Sailing!
Membership Renewal
Privacy settings.
Key details
Policy prepared by:
John Thompson
Approved by committee:
13/06/18
Policy became operational on:
13/06/18
Next review date:
13/06/19
Summary of the Data Privacy measures.
·      We only collect personal information about you where it is completely necessary, or you have given consent.
·      We collect member’s personal data so that we can provide the most suitable activities to support their interests in water-based activities at Ardleigh.  This includes; contacting them if their boats are in danger from the weather informing them that they need to inspect their craft and how it is secured.   Reminding them of their club duties.
·      We will not send you marketing material unless you have given permission.
·      We will not sell your personal information to third parties.
·      We use reputable suppliers to help us securely store your data in accordance with current data protection laws.  Your data may be transferred to countries outside the European Economic Union (EEA).  When this happens, we will ensure that any party that can access your information has implemented the necessary security and privacy measures that will ensure your data is kept secure and confidential, as outlined in this policy.
·      We will protect your personal information with an appropriate combination of technical and organisational measures.
·      We will not retain your data any longer than it is necessary to do so.  For example, for club members this will be 3 months after both the receipt of resignation, and when all outstanding dues have been paid to the club.
·      You have a right to see the data we hold about you.  We will provide this information within one calendar month of verifying your identity after receiving your request.
·      If you have any complaint, or have any questions about this Privacy policy, then please email committee@ardleighsc.co.uk, or talk to a member of the committee at the club.  You also have the right to complain to the Information Commissioner’s Office.
Data Protection Policy verison 1.0Context and Overview
Key details
Policy prepared by:
John Thompson
Approved by committee:
13/06/18
Policy became operational on:
13/06/18
Next review date:
13/06/19
Introduction
Ardleigh Sailing Club needs to gather and use certain information about members of the club and affiliated organisations
This policy describes how this personal data must be collected, handled and stored to meet the organisation’s data protection standards — and to comply with the law.
Why this policy exists
This data protection policy ensures Ardleigh Sailing Club:
·      Complies with data protection law and follows good practice
·      Protects the rights of committee, members and affiliates
·      Is open about how it stores and processes individuals’ data
Protects itself from the risks of a data breach
Data protection law
General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), which replaces the Data Protection Act 1918 on 25th May 2018, describes how organisations, including Ardleigh Sailing Club, must collect, handle and store personal information.  These rules apply regardless of whether data is stored electronically, on paper or on other materials.
To comply with the law, personal information must be collected and used fairly, stored safely and not disclosed unlawfully. The Data Protection Act is underpinned by eight important principles. These say that personal data must:
1.     Be processed fairly and lawfully
2.     Be obtained only for specific, lawful purposes
3.     Be adequate, relevant and not excessive
4.     Be accurate and kept up to date
5.     Not be held for any longer than necessary
6.     Processed in accordance with the rights of data subjects
7.     Be protected in appropriate ways
Not be transferred outside the European Economic Area (EEA), unless that country or territory also ensures an adequate level of protection
People, risks and responsibilities
Policy scope
This policy applies to all data that the club holds relating to identifiable members.  This can include:
·      Names of individuals
·      Postal addresses
·      Email addresses
·      Telephone numbers
·      Photographs
…plus any other information relating to individuals
Responsibilities
Everyone associated with Ardleigh Sailing Club has some responsibility for ensuring data is collected, stored and handled appropriately.
Each member that handles personal data to carry out a task given to them by the club must ensure that it is handled and processed in line with this policy and data protection principles.  However, the committee is ultimately responsible for ensuring that Ardleigh Sailing Club meets its legal obligations.
General guidelines
·      The only people able to access data covered by this policy should be those who need it to carry out their work for the club.
·      Data should not be shared informally.
·      All members should keep all data secure, by taking sensible precautions and following the guidelines below.
·      In particular, strong passwords must be used and they should never be shared.
·      Personal data should not be disclosed to unauthorised people, either within the company or externally.
·      Data should be regularly reviewed and updated if it is found to be out of date. If no longer required, it should be deleted and disposed of.
Data storage
When data is stored on paper, it should be kept in a secure place where unauthorised people cannot see it.
These guidelines also apply to data that is usually stored electronically but has been printed out for some reason:
When not required, the paper or files should be kept in a locked drawer or filing cabinet.
Data Administrators should ensure paper and printouts are not left where unauthorised people could see them, like on a printer.
Data printouts should be shredded and disposed of securely when no longer required.
When data is stored electronically, it must be protected from unauthorised access, accidental deletion and malicious hacking attempts:
Unless there an identifiable need Data should only be stored on the clubs Wild Apricot database.
Data should be protected by strong passwords that are changed regularly and never shared.
If data is stored on removable media (like a CD or DVD), these should be kept locked away securely when not being used.
Data should be backed up frequently.  Those backups should be tested regularly, at least once every 6 months.
·      Data should never be saved directly to laptops or other mobile devices like tablets or smart phones.
Data use
·      When working with personal data, members should ensure the screens of their computers are always locked when left unattended.
·      Personal data should not be shared informally. In particular, it should never be sent by email, as this form of communication is not secure.
·      Personal data should never be transferred outside of the European Economic Area.
·      Members should not save copies of personal data to their own computers. Always access and update the central copy of any data.
·      Ardleigh sailing club will not authorise any member to publish any photograph on their website, other websites and on social media unless all individuals that can be identified in the photograph have given their permission.
·      If members wish to publish on websites, social media etc. any photographs taken at Ardleigh Sailing Club they should ensure that they have permission to publish the photograph from anyone who could be recognised from that photograph.
Data accuracy
The law requires Ardleigh Sailing Club to take reasonable steps to ensure data is kept accurate and up to date. It is the responsibility of all members who work with data to take reasonable steps to ensure it is kept as accurate and up to date as possible.
Data will be only held on the Wild Apricot Database.
Data should be updated as inaccuracies are discovered. For instance, if a member can no longer be reached on their stored telephone number, it should be removed from the database.
Disclosing data for other reasons
In certain circumstances, the Data Protection Act allows personal data to be disclosed to law enforcement agencies without the consent of the data subject.  Under these circumstances Ardleigh Sailing Club will disclose requested data. However, the committee will ensure the request is legitimate, seeking legal advice where necessary.
© Ardleigh Sailing Club | Find Us
Powered by Wild Apricot Membership Software
